A Guide to the Kirkpatrick Property Photograph Collection, ca. 1992
Thomas Balch Library
Thomas Balch Library
Kirkpatrick Property Photograph Collection ca. 1992
Thomas Balch Library
VC 0028
This collection consists of 46 3"x5" color photographs, taken by Steve Nicklin in approximately 1992. The images capture the exterior of outbuildings and the grounds of the 3.5 acre Kirkpatrick estate as well as the interior and exterior of the main house.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection open for research.
Acquisition Information
Steve Nicklin, Bowling Green, VA
Alternative Form Available
None
Accruals
2009.0117
Historical Information
In 1952, Herbert Kirkpatrick (1895-1976) purchased 12.5 acres at the southeast corner of Harrison Street, now Morven Park Road NW, and Waterford Road, now Old Waterford Road NW, Leesburg, Virginia, from Daniel (1907-1985) and Ernestine Chamblin (1909-1994). Aerial photography from 1957 shows the existence of improvements on the property, which had an address of 66 Morven Park Road, later readdressed to 136 Morven Park Road NW.
In 1969, Kirkpatrick and his wife Annie (1905-1993) sold the northerly 8.4 acres to Southeastern Builders, Inc. Southeastern Builders subdivided and developed the subdivision into 28 residences along Old Waterford Road, Morven Park Road, Morven Park Court NW, and the north side of Ayrlee Avenue NW. In 1994, the Kirpatrick children Raymond, William and Jean normalized the boundary between Annie's estate and the .4 acre parcel belonging to Raymond at 132 Morven Park Road NW, which had originally been part of 4 acre parcel remaining after the 1969 subdivision.
In late 1997, the Kirkpatrick heirs sold the remainder of Annie's estate to Grove at Morven Park, LLC, which subsequently developed the property into 13 residences along Morven Park Road, the south side of Ayrlee Avenue NW, and the west end of Daniels Street NW. Documentation indicates that demolition of the original Kirkpatrick home and outbuildings at 136 Morven Park Road was authorized in June 1998.
Scope and Content
This collection consists of 46 3"x5" color photographs, taken by Steve Nicklin in approximately 1992. The images capture the exterior of outbuildings and the grounds of the 3.5 acre Kirkpatrick estate as well as the interior and exterior of the main house.
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Bibliography
Aerial photograph of Leesburg, Virginia, 1957. Town of Leesburg, Department of Planning and Zoning.
Aerial photograph of Leesburg, Virginia, 1986, Map Collection, Thomas Balch Library, Leesburg, VA.
Aerial Photo Map of Leesburg, Virginia, 2000, Map Collection, Thomas Balch Library, Leesburg, VA.
Ancestry Library Edition, Social Security Death Index, www.ancestrylibrary.com.
County of Loudoun, Department of Building & Development, Permit No. B-89298.
Deed Book 13-Z: 438. Loudoun County Circuit Court, Leesburg, Virginia.
Deed Book 505: 148. Loudoun County Circuit Court, Leesburg, Virginia.
Deed Book 1302: 547. Loudoun County Circuit Court, Leesburg, Virginia.
Deed Book 1564: 1563. Loudoun County Circuit Court, Leesburg, Virginia.
Leesburg, VA Air Photo Map, Air Photographics, Inc., 1969, Map Collection, Thomas Balch Library, Leesburg, VA.
The Town of Leesburg in Virginia: New Addresses, July 1, 1984; Town of Leesburg Records, RG 01 Mayor and Council, Thomas Balch Library, Leesburg, VA.
Will Book 118: 996. Loudoun County Circuit Court, Leesburg, Virginia.
Other Finding Aid
Past Perfect catalogue records
Technical Requirements
None
Related Material
None
Contents List
- [boxwoods at 136 Morven Park Rd NW], ca. 1992
- [evergreen trees at 136 Morven Park Rd NW], ca. 1992
- [lawn at 136 Morven Park Rd NW], ca. 1992
- [lawn at 136 Morven Park Rd NW], ca. 1992
- [corner landscaping at 136 Morven Park Rd NW], ca. 1992
- [landscaping at 136 Morven Park Rd NW], ca. 1992
- [lawn at 136 Morven Park Rd NW], ca. 1992
- [lawn at 136 Morven Park Rd NW], ca. 1992
- [drive way at 136 Morven Park Rd NW], ca. 1992
- [drive way at 136 Morven Park Rd NW], ca. 1992
- [landscaping at 136 Morven Park Rd NW], ca. 1992
- [landscaping at 136 Morven Park Rd NW], ca. 1992
- [landscaping at 136 Morven Park Rd NW], ca. 1992
- [landscaping at 136 Morven Park Rd NW], ca. 1992
- [outbuilding at 136 Morven Park Rd NW], ca. 1992
- [outbuilding at 136 Morven Park Rd NW], ca. 1992
- [main house at 136 Morven Park Rd NW], ca. 1992
- [main house at 136 Morven Park Rd NW], ca. 1992
- [main house at 136 Morven Park Rd NW], ca. 1992
- [outbuilding at 136 Morven Park Rd NW], ca. 1992
- [main house at 136 Morven Park Rd NW], ca. 1992
- [main house at 136 Morven Park Rd NW], ca. 1992
- [main house at 136 Morven Park Rd NW], ca. 1992
- [main house at 136 Morven Park Rd NW], ca. 1992
- [lawn at 136 Morven Park Rd NW], ca. 1992
- [outbuilding at 136 Morven Park Rd NW], ca. 1992
- [outbuilding at 136 Morven Park Rd NW], ca. 1992
- [outbuilding at 136 Morven Park Rd NW], ca. 1992
- [main house at 136 Morven Park Rd NW], ca. 1992
- [main house at 136 Morven Park Rd NW], ca. 1992
- [basement at 136 Morven Park Rd NW], ca. 1992
- [basement at 136 Morven Park Rd NW], ca. 1992
- [entryway at 136 Morven Park Rd NW], ca. 1992
- [fireplace & hutch at 136 Morven Park Rd NW], ca. 1992
- [interior room at 136 Morven Park Rd NW], ca. 1992
- [bathroom at 136 Morven Park Rd NW], ca. 1992
- [interior room at 136 Morven Park Rd NW], ca. 1992
- [kitchen at 136 Morven Park Rd NW], ca. 1992
- [interior room at 136 Morven Park Rd NW], ca. 1992
- [interior room at 136 Morven Park Rd NW], ca. 1992
- [bedroom at 136 Morven Park Rd NW], ca. 1992
- [bedroom at 136 Morven Park Rd NW], ca. 1992
- [bedroom at 136 Morven Park Rd NW], ca. 1992
- [bedroom at 136 Morven Park Rd NW], ca. 1992
- [bedroom at 136 Morven Park Rd NW], ca. 1992
- [bedroom at 136 Morven Park Rd NW], ca. 1992